<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>

		<fileDesc>

			<titleStmt>
				<title>Hamlet as a kids' play</title>
				<respStmt>
					<resp>Based on</resp>
					<name>British Council's short story of Hamlet for kids</name>
				</respStmt>

				<respStmt>
					<resp>Edited by</resp>
					<name>DHDK student Lamargese Amelia Simonetta</name>
				</respStmt>
			</titleStmt>

			<publicationStmt>
				<p>Distributed privately for a university project</p>
			</publicationStmt>

			<sourceDesc>
				<p>No print source exists: this is an original digital text</p>
			</sourceDesc>

		</fileDesc>

		<encodingDesc>
			<projectDesc>
				<p>Texts collected and edited for a project for the Digital Text in the Humanities' course of the Digital Humanities and Digital Knowledge master's degree (University of Bologna)</p>
			</projectDesc>

			<schemaSpec ident="myTEI" docLang="en" xml:lang="en">
				<moduleRef key="drama"/>
				<moduleRef key="tei"/>
				<moduleRef key="header"/>
				<moduleRef key="textstructure"/>
			</schemaSpec>

			<tagsDecl>
				<namespace name="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
					<tagUsage gi="stage">This element is used for all stage directions</tagUsage>
				</namespace>	
			</tagsDecl>	

		</encodingDesc>	

		<profileDesc>
			<langUsage>
				<language ident="en">English</language>
			</langUsage>

			<textDesc n="play">
				<channel mode="ws">Written to be spoken. A play's text to be performed as drama.</channel>
				<constitution type="single"/>
				<derivation type="revision"/>
				<domain type="education"/>
				<factuality type="fiction"/>
				<interaction type="complete" active="plural" passive="group"/>
				<preparedness type="scripted"/>
				<purpose type="persuade" degree="high"/>
				<purpose type="entertain" degree="medium"/>
			</textDesc>

			<settingDesc>
				<p>Denmark</p>
			</settingDesc>

		</profileDesc>

	</teiHeader>

    <text>
        <front>

            <docTitle>
				<titlePart>HAMLET</titlePart>
			</docTitle>

            <set>
                <p>The story is set in Denmark</p>
            </set>

            <div type="Dramatis_Personae">
                <castList>
                    <castItem>
                        <role>Hamlet</role>
                        <roleDesc>Protagonist</roleDesc>
                    </castItem>

                    <castItem>
                        <role>Ghost</role>
                        <roleDesc>Ghost of Hamlet's father, Deuteragonist</roleDesc>
                    </castItem>

                    <castItem>
                        <role>Gertrude</role>
                        <roleDesc>Hamlet's mother</roleDesc>
                    </castItem>

                    <castItem>
                        <role>Claudius</role>
                        <roleDesc>Hamlet's uncle, the antagonist</roleDesc>
                    </castItem>

                    <castItem>
                        <role>Horatio</role>
                        <roleDesc>Hamlet's friend, Confidante</roleDesc>
                    </castItem>

                    <castItem>
                        <role>Ophelia</role>
                        <roleDesc>Hamlet's girlfriend, Love interest</roleDesc>
                    </castItem>

                    <castItem>
                        <role>Laertes</role>
                        <roleDesc>Ophelia's brother</roleDesc>
                    </castItem>

                    <castGroup>
                        <head>the Actors</head>

                        <castItem>
                            <role>Actor 1</role>
                        </castItem>

                        <castItem>
                            <role>Actor 2</role>
                        </castItem>
                    </castGroup>    

                    <castGroup>
                        <head>Narrators</head>
                        
                        <castItem>
                            <role>Narrator 1</role>
                            <roleDesc>Narrator of Scene 1</roleDesc>
                        </castItem>
                    
                        <castItem>
                            <role>Narrator 2</role>
                            <roleDesc>Narrator of Scene 2</roleDesc>
                        </castItem>
                        
                        <castItem>
                            <role>Narrator 3</role>
                            <roleDesc>Narrator of Scene 3</roleDesc>
                        </castItem>
                        
                        <castItem>
                            <role>Narrator 4</role>
                            <roleDesc>Narrator of Scene 4</roleDesc>
                        </castItem>
                    </castGroup>	

                </castList>
            </div>
        </front>

        <body>
            <div type="scene">
                <head>SCENE 1</head>

                <stage>Narrator 1, Hamlet, Gertrude, Claudius</stage>

                <stage type="entrance">(Narrator 1 enters the scene and goes to the left corner of the stage. Hamlet goes in the middle of the main stage and sits)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 1</speaker>
                    <p>Many years ago in Denmark there was a prince called Hamlet. One day Hamlet’s father, the king, dies suddenly and Hamlet is very sad.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet puts his head on his knees and cries)</stage>

                <stage type="entrance">(Gertrude and Claudius go behind Hamlet, one in front of each other and they hold their hands)</stage>    

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 1</speaker>
                    <p>After this, Hamlet’s mother, Gertrude, gets married again very quickly. She marries her husband’s brother, Claudius, and Claudius is now the king!</p>
                </sp>         

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet stands up, he moves towards one side of the stage and looks at his mother, angry and sad)</stage>   

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Hamlet</speaker>
                    <p>How could you do this to me!</p>
                </sp>     

                <stage type="exit">(everybody leaves the scene)</stage>
            </div>

            <div type="scene">
                <head>SCENE 2</head>

                <stage>Hamlet, Narrator 2, Horatio, Ghost, Ophelia</stage>

                <stage type="entrance">(Narrator 2 goes to the left front corner of the stage. Hamlet goes in the middle of the stage and Horatio runs towards him)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 2</speaker>
                    <p>One night Hamlet’s friend, Horatio, tells him that there is a ghost in the castle</p>
                </sp>   

                <stage type="gesture">(Horatio, frightened, touches Hamlet's arm to catch his attention)</stage>    

                <stage type="entrance">(The Ghost enters the scene and walks slowly towards Hamlet)</stage>

                <stage type="gesture">(Horatio points at the Ghost with his finger. The Ghost stops when he reaches Hamlet)</stage>

                <stage type="exit">(As soon as the Ghost stops near Hamlet, Horatio runs away and exits the scene)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 2</speaker>
                    <p>It is the ghost of Hamlet’s father!</p>
                </sp>    

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Ghost</speaker>
                    <p>Claudius killed me with poison! Hamlet, you must punish Claudius for me!</p>
                </sp> 

                <stage type="exit">(The Ghost leaves)</stage>

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet touches his head)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 2</speaker>
                    <p>Hamlet is confused. He doesn’t know if he believes the ghost and he doesn’t know what to do.</p>
                </sp> 

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet starts walking around and touches his chin)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 2</speaker>
                    <p>Hamlet now acts very strangely. He is mean and angry, and he upsets his girlfriend, Ophelia.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="entrance">(Ophelia enters the scene, runs towards Hamlet and hugs him)</stage>

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet pushes Ophelia away)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Hamlet</speaker>
                    <p>Go away! Leave me alone!</p>
                </sp>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Ophelia</speaker>
                    <p>Oh, he is so mean!</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="exit">(Ophelia runs away exiting from one side and Hamlet walks away exiting the scene from the opposite side)</stage>

            </div>

            <div type="scene">
                <head>SCENE 3</head>

                <stage>The Actors, Hamlet, Claudius, Narrator 3</stage>

                <stage type="entrance">(Narrator 3 goes to the left front corner of the stage. The Actors and Hamlet go in the middle, facing each other)</stage>

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet and the Actors are talking without voice)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 3</speaker>
                    <p>One day a group of actors come to the castle and Hamlet makes a plan. He asks the actors to change their play. The new play will show a king poisoned like Hamlet’s father.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet steps in the middle, facing the public)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Hamlet</speaker>
                    <p>With this play I will catch the king.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet goes besides the Narrator and looks at the scene)</stage>

                <stage type="entrance">(Claudius enters and sits in the middle of the right side of the stage, looking at the Actors)</stage>

                <stage type="gesture">(Actor 1 gives a cup to Actor 2, who drinks from the cup and falls dead on the floor.</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 3</speaker>
                    <p>When Claudius watches the play he looks very worried and runs away. Hamlet sees him and he knows the truth.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="exit">(Claudius looks around him, very worried, then stands up and runs out of the scene)</stage>

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet runs near the Actors and points with his finger at the exit from where Claudius ran away)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Hamlet</speaker>
                    <p>I knew it!</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="exit">(Everybody leaves)</stage>
            </div>

            <div type="scene">
                <head>SCENE 4</head>

                <stage>Narrator 4, Hamlet, Claudius, Laertes, Gertrude, Horatio</stage>

                <stage type="entrance">(Narrator 4 goes in the left front corner of the main stage. Hamlet goes near the Narrator, while Claudius and Laertes go to the middle of the stage, talking at a low voice - indistinctly)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 4</speaker>
                    <p>Claudius is very worried about Hamlet now and makes a plan with Ophelia’s brother, Laertes.</p>
                </sp>    

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Claudius</speaker>
                    <p>You will fight him and we will put poison on the sword and in his drink too.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="entrance">(Gertude enters and sits in the right side of the stage)</stage>

                <stage type="gesture">(Claudius goes in the right side of the stage, sitting next to Gertrude, while Hamlet goes in the middle and starts fighting Laertes with swords.)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 4</speaker>
                    <p>Laertes and Hamlet fight. Laertes cuts Hamlet, but in the fight Hamlet takes Laertes’ sword and cuts him with it too!</p>
                </sp> 

                <stage type="gesture">(Laertes cuts Hamlet. Hamlet touches the cut on his body, takes Laertes' sword and cuts him. Laertes lays down and slowly dies)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Gertrude</speaker>
                    <p>Here, Hamlet, drink this.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="gesture">(Gertrude takes a cup in her hand)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Hamlet</speaker>
                    <p>No, thank you, Mother. I’m not thirsty.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="gesture">(Gertrude drinks from the cup. Claudius looks at her)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Claudius</speaker>
                    <p>No, don't!</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="gesture">(Gertrude suffocates and dies)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Hamlet</speaker>
                    <p>It was him! He poisoned us all!</p>
                </sp>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 4</speaker>
                    <p>Finally, Hamlet knows he must stop Claudius.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="gesture">(Hamlet goes to Claudius and kills him with the sword. Claudius dies. Hamlet falls on his knees and lays down pushing the hands on the cut on his body)</stage>

                <stage type="entrance">(Horatio enters the scene running to help Hamlet. He sits down next to Hamlet and touches his hands)</stage>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Narrator 4</speaker>
                    <p>All the royal family are now poisoned and Hamlet tells his friend that there must be a new king.</p>
                </sp>

                <sp>
                    <speaker>Horatio</speaker>
                    <p>Goodbye, my prince.</p>
                </sp>

                <stage type="exit">(Curtain closes)</stage>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>            
</TEI>    